<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-18T20:37:31-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">One Sparkplug</title><subtitle>This is Andy's website.  Anything can happen here.</subtitle><author><name>Andy Vaselaar</name></author><entry><title type="html">First Dirt</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/alaska/2018/06/18/firstdirt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Dirt" /><published>2018-06-18T20:34:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-06-18T20:34:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/alaska/2018/06/18/firstdirt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/alaska/2018/06/18/firstdirt.html">&lt;p&gt;First Dirt!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day started out pretty ordinary.  I woke up and looked at the radar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/20180618/radar_route.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rain it is, then.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yay, rain!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I packed the normal way, trying to shove my clothes in the box with it still on the bike.  But, they kept falling out, and after the 5th try, I gave up and decided to use gravity to help me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/20180618/20180618_074533.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pushover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry, its fine.  I managed to push it over on soft ground at least twice more today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting packed up, I headed for Forsyth, MT where I stopped for fuel, and then continued along Hwy 12.  That was a super pretty drive, with almost no traffic, though the wide open plains.  It follows an old rail bed and if you watch the odometer you can pick up on the roughly 20 mile spacing of towns for trains back in the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/20180618/20180618_100119.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Road 12&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, the Garmin put a funny kink in the path I was to follow, taking me off 12.  This wasn’t on google maps.  When I turned onto it, there was a sign that said “Pavement ends - 8 miles.”  Sounds like fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, after 8 miles, it turned into a nice gravel road.  Which soon degraded to a dirt path.  If I were in the pickup, I would have turned around (it tends to get stuck on anything that isn’t dry pavement), but this is the kind of thing the bike was made for.  Some of the sections got a little slick and sloppy, but as long as you let the bike just keep rolling, the gyroscopic forces will keep you upright.  At least thats the theory, and it worked well today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for this little transgression from the pavement, I was rewarded with a little bit shorter ride, and some tremendous views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/20180618/20180618_105755.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;dirt view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/20180618/20180618_114005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;dirt view 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bike stayed clean for an entire 2.5 days, that might be a new record!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/20180618/20180618_115129.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;dirty bike&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting to pavement on road 200, I rode toward Lewistown, the place I had intended to stay last night.  It looked like a really nice little town, complete with a cafe where I had a tasty monte christo sandwich and some coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onwward from there to Great Falls I followed 200 until it met 87, and then followed 87 all the way to Great Falls.  This was another pretty ride, with lots of hills, plains and even a couple of mountains.  It wsa wet and rainy the whole way, with a chilly wind out of the North.  I had the heated jacket on, and I think the bike might have wanted one too.  The temperature gauge hovered near the bottom pretty much the whole way, but would creep up a back toward normal whenever the crosswind was blocked.  Brr!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonights camp is at Dick’s RV Park in Great Falls, MT.  Its okay, I guess.  Cheaper than the KOA, the only other game in town.  It could be worse, I could be one of those motorcyclists the lady at the desk told me about - stuck on top of Beartooth Pass in a whiteout.  In June.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Vaselaar</name></author><category term="alaska" /><summary type="html">First Dirt!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/alaska/2018/06/17/rain.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rain" /><published>2018-06-17T20:34:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-06-17T20:34:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/alaska/2018/06/17/rain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/alaska/2018/06/17/rain.html">&lt;p&gt;Rain!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I went to bed last night, it was just starting to rain.  When I woke up at 5am, it was still raining.  When I woke up again at 8, it was still raining.  I really like a good rainstorm, but I think Spearfish is overdoing it a bit.””&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/20180617/20180617_092756.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I hate packing wet tents&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/20180617/20180617_092810.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Squish squish&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After packing everything inside trash bags inside their usual containers, I loaded up the bike, went and bought more trash bags (for next time), and stopped in at Blackbird Espresso to enjoy a warm cup of coffee and a sandwich.  That was a good move, they had really comfy chairs and a warm place to sit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the coffee was gone, I hopped back on the bike and rode out of town toward Belle Fourche, hoping to make it all to Lewistown, Montana.  A lofty goal, but it would have been over halfway to Glacier National Park.  No dice though, cold rain, lots of pit stops, and a super late start ruled that out.   Also, more hiccups made my throat feel pretty rough (a benadryl solved that later though).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do though that when travelling by motorcycle is that it is really easy to talk to you.  Regular people think you’re nuts, dress like a ninja, and are curious what it is you’re actually up to.  Motorcyclists want to know if you’re as cold as them, how your trip is going, and where you’re headed.  The people you run into is definitely one of my favorite aspects of this kind of travel.  I talked to 4 different people about my trip today from Florida, Oregon, South Dakota and Minnesota.  Pretty fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big news of today is I got to test out my heated jacket, and it is far better than sliced bread.  Think of it like wearing a warm hug as you go down the road on a chilly day.  I didn’t turn it up much, just enough to keep the chill off and keep be from worrying about being cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/20180617/20180617_151106.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Clouds breaking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed at Big Sky RV park on the edge of town Miles City, Montana.  Not a bad place to stay the night if you’re coming through, although you should definitely bring bug repellant if they’ve had an usual amount of rain like they have this year.  Also the ground was super soft, even the tires on my bike left a dent in the ground where I parked; the kickstand headed straight for China.  Fortunately not only can you cook on a grill, you can lean a bike against it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/20180617/20180617_193054.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Miles City&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dinner was a delicious can of campbells soup, cooked the second laziest way possible.  To make it fancy I sliced up an avocado to go with it :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/20180617/20180617_201732.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dinner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Vaselaar</name></author><category term="alaska" /><summary type="html">Rain!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hiccups</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/alaska/2018/06/16/hiccups.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hiccups" /><published>2018-06-16T20:34:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T20:34:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/alaska/2018/06/16/hiccups</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/alaska/2018/06/16/hiccups.html">&lt;p&gt;The first day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day is never easy.  Lots of hugs, lots of pictures, some more hugs, some goodbyes, and then you hop on your trusty steed and head away for a journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those first ten miles are a mix of joy and relaxation as you realize all you have to do the rest of the day is ride along and stop for gas on occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, as you’ve just left a stopsign, you hear the characteristic CLUNK CLUNK skiiiiiiiiid noise of your pelican boxes falling off your bike and skittering across the pavement.  Fortunately, you’re on a two lane road in Iowa, not the interestate.  Upon investigation, I found that the pins that hold the boxes on the bike can work themselves out if the boxes rock back and forth - and its made worse when they’re full, so I didn’t find it when I installed them.  I did some precision roadside filing with my leatherman and got the pins to seat better so it takes more bouncing before they’ll come off, screwed in the “extra security” knobs on the inside of the box, and then strapped them down anyway so they won’t move.  They weren’t a problem the rest of the day, thankfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride across South Dakota was pretty uneventful.  Warm, with wind out of the south, which gradually turned to the north as I got closer to Rapid City.  Gas milage wasn’t amazing - between 37 and 45, depending on the wind.  Probably the worse part was getting stung in the neck, by some sort of insect as I climbed the entrance ramp after getting gas once.  I’m pretty sure that this is what gave me a case of the hiccups the rest of the day, and all of the morning the next day.  What fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wall Drug and their hundreds of signs along I-90 did not disappoint.  I stopped in for a picture with their jackalope, some stickers, and one of their tasty donuts.   Everything else seemed a bit overpriced - $5.79 for a thing of floss?  Its worth a stop anyway just to see how something 100% touristy can be interesting in its own way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to Spearfish somewhere around 6pm local time, setup camp in Spearfish City Park, and grabbed a burrito at Barbacoas.  Apparently it is now $25 to camp in the park; it was free when I was here 7 years ago.  I’m not really surprised at the change, they do a really nice job keeping it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than the hours upon hours of rain, it was an uneventful stay, thankfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next stop, Lewistown, Montana!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Vaselaar</name></author><category term="alaska" /><summary type="html">The first day!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intentional Living</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/alaska/2018/05/07/intent.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intentional Living" /><published>2018-05-07T20:34:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-05-07T20:34:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/alaska/2018/05/07/intent</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/alaska/2018/05/07/intent.html">&lt;p&gt;In the last last couple of years, I’ve realized a few things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, this may be obvious, but we humans don’t live forever (yet).  I’m 34, and looking back from here, life has a been a blur.  A twisty, turny, crazy, blur.  As it turns out, nothing I expected when I graduated from high school, college, or graduate school really materialized the way I expected. That said - what DID I expect?  I’m not really sure that I know.  Honestly, that isn’t that surprising to me now, but I think that high school senior eating fajitas on graduation day probably wouldn’t believe me.  The reason that this all got stirred up is that in the last couple years I felt myself settling into auto pilot. I had a secure job, a house, and a daily routine that left me thinking “Is this it? Do I spend the rest of my days like this?”  That wasn’t the state of mind I wanted to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, we all have bucket lists and it seems the number of items on the list only gets larger.  If we want it shorter, we have to really make an effort to check off the items, or cross them out as we give up on them.  As I looked at my own list, I realized I’d have to start crossing things out if I didn’t get a move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, most of the things on my bucket list take time.  When I talk about visiting somewhere, I really want to spend some time there; try the local cuisine, see the local spots, relax a bit.  Maybe even pretend that I live there.  I know I’d have a hard time with something like a cruise where you only get a few hours to wander around a destination.  This desire to loiter is directly in conflict with the amount of vacation time we are typically alotted in the working world.  At my last job, it was 3 weeks per year - including sick days.  Throw in some family time, maybe a wedding or a funeral, a couple of three day weekend trips, and the holidays, and that vanishes pretty quickly.  Its even worse if you have kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like the most normal thing to do is just to save up that bucket list, and save up the retirement account, and then put the two together someday.  I really am not a fan of this plan - there are zero guarantees that I will make it that far, and if I do, I may not be healthy enough to do much besides sit around and watch TV.  There are plenty of people who never make it to retirement, and still more who are too worn out once they get there to really enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after the last four years of my life evaporated away in an unproductive blur with little progress on my bucket list, I decided that it was time for a change.  I needed to live more intentionally - cut out things that don’t matter and clear space for that which does.  Not only that, but I’m changing the way I make my living, both to facilitate my desire to travel and to support my sanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first item on that bucket list is Alaska.  Now I have the time, the savings, and a perfectly good motorcycle.  Time to put this new life strategy to the test.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Vaselaar</name></author><category term="alaska" /><summary type="html">In the last last couple of years, I’ve realized a few things.</summary></entry></feed>